A Guide to the Lindsley F. Kimball papers FA1164
Rockefeller Archive Center
Lindsley F. Kimball papers
1944-1978
Rockefeller Archive Center
Kimball, Lindsley F. (1894-1992)
Rockefeller, John D., Jr. (John Davison) (1874-1960)
FA1164
1.69 Cubic Feet 1 standard record storage box and 1 letter document box
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Collection includes but is not limited to: studies pertaining to JDR Jr's interests including: the history of USO, a guide to long-range planning for United Way, Commission on the Future of Rockefeller University and Kimball's files for Riverside Church, New York Blood Center, New York College of Osteopathic Medicine and the Red Cross.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred to RAC as Accession 1983:033.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Lindsley F. Kimball served as an associate of John D. Rockefeller Jr. in the Rockefeller family office (Room 5600).
- Duke University - Conference of Corporate Chief Executives - The Third Sector - A New Perspective on Corporate Social Responsibilies, 1977 October 19 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- John D. Rockefeller (1839-1937) - Industrial Pioneer and Man, by W. Trevor Holliday, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- New York Blood Center, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- New York Blood Center - The Lindsley F. Kimball Research Institute, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- New York City Financial Crisis, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- New York College of Osteopathic Medicine (NYCOM), 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
- Red Cross, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Scope and Contents
  American Red Cross and International Committee
- Riverside Church - Mark M. Jones Study to the Joint Committee of Trustees and Deacons, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Riverside Church - Reports, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Contains Lindsley F. Kimball report and also contains Harry E. Fosdick report "Policy and Program of the Riverside Church".
- Rockefeller University - Report of the Committee on the Future of the University, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- United Service Organizations (USO) - Reports, 1944-1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- United Service Organizations (USO) - History of the USO, Part I (Chester I. Barnard) (Box 1, Folder 14)
- United Service Organizations (USO) - History of the USO, Part II (Julia M. H. Carson) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- United Way - Guides to Long-Range Planning in the United Way System, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Yale University - Study of Independent Institutions, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Lindsley F. Kimball, 1036; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box, 1 folder
  Portraits, Groups, Awards.
  Photographs
  - Lindsley F. Kimball (Box 14, Folder 179)